Historical Reference, University; Collection ua950.008
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Tradition of Excellence: The Sesquicentennial History of the University at Albany, State University of New York, 1844 to 1994 (Volume 27)
  - Tradition of Excellence Photographs: Chapters 6-8, 1994 (Volume 30)
    - Page 138 C-Bottom Left: Mathematics professor Violet Larney began teaching at Albany in 1952 and saw the transition of mathematics from an undergraduate teaching department to a graduate and research-oriented unit.
    - Page 138 D-Bottom Right: Catherine Wolkonsky, a Russian émigré scholar, had retired from Vassar College when she came to Albany and established a tradition of interest in Russian language and literature., Undated
    - Page 139 A-Top: Randolph Gardner and Richard Teevan., 1969
    - Page 139 B-Bottom Left: Collegium Arcanum members (l to r) M.I. Berger, Richard Kendall, Harry Staley, Walter Knotts, Morris Eson, Kendall Birr and Arthur Collins, Undated
    - Page 139 C-Bottom Right: Professors Samuel McGee-Russell and Robert Allen. (photograph missing), Undated
    - Page 140 A-Top: Members of the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center on a field trip to Yellowstone., Undated
    - Page 140 B-Bottom: Professor Ray Falconer of the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center., Undated
    - Page 142: "The Cave" in Husted Cafeteria., 1965-1966
    - Page 143: U.N. Secretary General U Thant visited the campus in 1966 as part of a University Seminar Series on Peaceful Change.
    - Page 144: Page 1 of the student publication Suppression, 1962
    - Page 145: Janis Joplin performing on campus., 1969
    - Page 146: Evan Rever Collins (photograph missing), Undated
    - Page 147 A-Top: Group photo of the women's softball team., 1968-1969
    - Page 147 B-Bottom: Action shot of the men's soccer team., Undated
    - Page 148: 1971 Telethon participants.
    - Page 149 A-Top: Students in a dorm room with a guitar., Undated
    - Page 149 B-Bottom: Students outdoors with a keg., 1968 May 12
    - Page 150 A-Top: Dr. Judith Mysliborski, '69, a dermatologist in the Albany area. (photograph missing), Undated
    - Page 150 B-Bottom: Robert Peterkin, '66, MA '76, formerly superintendent of Milwaukee schools., Undated
    - Page 151 A-Top: Drew Zambelli, Secretary to Governor Mario Cuomo., ca. 1994
    - Page 151 B-Bottom: Harriet Dyer Adams, MLS '60 and former head of the University Libraries Special Collections in the 1970s., Undated
    - Page 152: Sigma Tau Beta, winners of the prize for best float in the 1969 Homecoming Parade.
    - Page 153 A-Left: Alice Hastings Murphy, MLS '40, speaking at the dedication of the libraries., 1968
    - Page 153 B-Right: President Evan R. Collins at the formal dedication of the new campus., 1969 May 17
    - Page 154: Dialogue Days: Acting President Allan Kuusisto canceled classes following student demonstrations., 1970 March
    - Page 156: Congressman Ogden Reid address a Vietnam Moratorium on the Podium., 1969 October 15
    - Page 157: Attorney William Kunstler speaking to a crowd of 6,000 on campus., 1970 March 5
    - Page 158: A protest in support of the Black Panthers at the State Capitol., 1970 March
    - Page 159: A protest on Alumni Quad against the state's action during the Attica Prison uprising., 1971 September
    - Page 160: Carl Martin, a counselor in the Educational Opportunities Program meets with a student., Undated
    - Page 161: Graduates of the Educational Opportunities Program from the Class of 1974
    - Page 162: Louis T. Benezet succeeded Evan Collins as President in 1970 after a year-long term by Acting President Kuusisto., Undated
    - Page 163: Harry L. Hamilton, professor of atmospheric science, speaks at a Senate meeting. Students focused on gaining membership in the University Senate in 1969., Undated
    - Page 164: Seth Spellman of the School of Social Welfare led the James E. Allen Collegiate Center., Undated
    - Page 165: Dr. Nathan Wright was among the earliest members and the first chair of the Afro-American Studies Department., Undated
    - Page 166: Philip Sirotkin, Vice President for Academic Affairs., Undated
    - Page 167: (l to r) Louis Salkever, Vice President for Research and Graduate Studies; unidentified; John Hartigan, Assistant Vice President for Finance; President Emmett Fields; and John Hartley, Vice President for Business and Finance., Undated
    - Page 168 A-Top: Biology professor John Mackiewicz was the first Albany faculty member promoted to "Distinguished" rank by the State University Board of Trustees in 1973., Undated
    - Page 168 B-Bottom: Kevin Burke of the Geological Sciences Department., Undated
    - Page 169: John Dewey of the Geological Sciences Department., Undated
    - Page 170 A-Top: Harry Crull, teacher of the astronomy department, lost in the financial crisis of the 1970s, Undated
    - Page 170 B-Bottom: Dean John Schumaker, Director M.E. Grenander and Deputy Director Hugh Maclean of the Institute for Humanistic Studies., Undated
    - Page 171 A-Top Left: Bernard K. Johnpoll of the Political Science department., Undated
    - Page 171 B-Top Right: Professor Marguerite Warren of the School of Criminal Justice., Undated
    - Page 171 C-Bottom: Ted Fossick served as principal of the Milne School from 1947-1973., Undated
    - Page 172: Professor Joan E. Schulz of the English Department. (photograph missing), Undated
    - Page 173 A-Top Left: Miles Davis, Undated
    - Page 173 B-Right: Aretha Franklin, Undated
    - Page 173 C-Bottom Left: Eric Clapton, Undated
    - Page 174 A-Left: Michael Lampert, '73, became a prominent litigator in New York and New Jersey., 1979 June 5
    - Page 174 B-Top Right: Fred Brewington '79 and Ray Gay, Co-captains of the 1977 football team.
    - Page 174 C-Bottom Right: Cathy Ladman, '75, a popular standup comic., Undated
    - Page 175 A-Top: A performance of Marat Sade in 1972 was directed by faculty member Jarka Burian.
    - Page 175 B-Bottom: Community-University Day: President Benezet and University Council Chairman J. Vanderbil Straub present a Key to the University to Mayor Erastus Corning 2 and Schenectady Mayor Frank Duci., 1972
    - Page 176: Physics Professor Alain Kaloyeros with graduate students., Undated
    - Page 178: Vincent O'Leary was named President in 1978 after serving for a year as Acting President. He was previously Dean of the School of Criminal Justice., Undated
    - Page 179 A-Top: Jeanna Gullahorn, Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies., Undated
    - Page 179 B-Bottom: Frank Pogue, Vice President for Student Affairs (1983-1987) (photograph missing), Undated
    - Page 180: Convocation and Procession for the Opening of the Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy. Grand Marshal Eugene McLaren of Chemistry leads, followed by Provost Warren and Commencement Speaker Alice Rivlin, former director of the Congressional Budget Office., 1983
    - Page 181 A-Top: Groundbreaking for the Freedom Quad. Albany Mayor Thomas M. Whalen is at the podium, with President O'Leary and University Council Chair Alan V. Iselin seated., 1986
    - Page 181 B-Bottom: Kris Kristofferson and Jane Fonda in the Campus Center's Assembly Hall, which was converted for the filming of the movie Rollover., 1980
    - Page 182 A-Top: Distinguished Teaching Professor Margaret Stewart of the Biological Sciences Department., Undated
    - Page 182 B-Bottom: Distinguished Service Professor James Corbett of the Physics Department (l) with Professor William Lanford (r). (photograph missing), Undated
    - Page 183 A-Top: Collins Fellow and Psychology Professor Shirley C. Brown., Undated
    - Page 183 B-Bottom Left: R. Findlay Cockrell of the Music Department., Undated
    - Page 183 C-Bottom Right: Edward Crowley of the Art Department., Undated
    - Page 184 A-Top: The Center for Women in Government: Ronnie Steiberg, director of research and implementation for the Center, Executive Director Nancy Perlman and State Commissioner of Public Service Karen Burnstein announce the findings of a study., 1983
    - Page 184 B-Bottom: David Barlow and Edward Blanchard, co-directors of the Center for Stress and Anxiety Disorders., 1985 December
    - Page 185: Richard Nathan, Distinguished Professor of Public Policy and Provost of the Rockefeller College., Undated
    - Page 186 A-Top: Political Activism returned in the 1980s, including protests to encourage the State University of New York to adopt a policy of divestment of holdings in companies doing business in South Africa until apartheid was eradicated., Undated
    - Page 186 B-Bottom: Students and Faculty set a Guinness World Record for largest game of musical chairs., 1985 April
    - Page 187: Michael Corso, '83, '84, was elected President of the Student Association in 1982-1983
    - Page 188: Richard "Doc" Sauers, Albany's basketball coach and faculty member in Physical Education since 1956, marked his 600th career victory in 1992, making him the winningest coach in NCAA Division III history., 1985
    - Page 189 A-Top: Albany's club crew team training on the Hudson River., Undated
    - Page 189 B-Bottom: Zoraida Davis, '91, star player on the women's softball team., Summer 1990
    - Page 190 A-Top: State Sen. Kenneth LaValle, Lisa LaValle, '86, President O'Leary and Governor Mario Cuomo at Commencement, 1986
    - Page 190 B-Bottom: Madeline Cuomo, '86., 1986
    - Page 191: Students on computers., Undated
    - Page 191 A-Top: Sung Bok Kim, Dean of Undergraduate Studies., Undated
    - Page 192 B-Bottom: Carson Carr Jr., Associate Dean and Director of the Educational Opportunities Program., Undated
    - Page 193: An aerial view of campus looking south. (photograph missing), 1981
    - Page 194: Dr. David Axelrod addressing the crowd at Commencement., 1990
    - Page 195: Governor Mario Cuomo chatting with student members of Purple and Gold following Commencement., 1986
    - Page 196: Sheri Dinkelsohn was Commencement student speaker in 1989.
    - Page 197: Fountain Day 1991.
    - Page 198: Ed Lemon, '94 carries the ball against St. Lawrence., 1993
    - Page 199: H. Patrick Swygert was appointed the fifteenth President of the University in 1990. (photograph missing), Undated
    - Page 200: President Swygert and Mrs. Sonja Swygert with members of Purple and Gold., 1991
    - Page 201 A-Top: Distinguished Service Professor Edna Acosta-Belen, '69, Ph.D. '77, is a member of the Department of Latin American and Caribbean Studies., Undated
    - Page 201 B-Bottom: Anthropologist Dean Falk., Undated
    - Page 202: The Authors and Editors Recognition Program., Undated
    - Page 203: Tom Smith, Professor of English and associate director of the New York Writers Institute addresses the Authors and Editors Recognition Program., Undated
    - Page 204: Fountain Day Festivities, 1992
    - Page 205: Spectators on Fountain Day. (photograph missing), 1993
    - Page 206: The University at Albany's State Legislative Delegation., 1993 April
    - Page 207 A-Top: Members of the University Council, 1993-1994
    - Page 207 B-Bottom: The 1993 Alumni(ae) leadership team.
    - Page 208: The 149th Commencement at Knickerbocker Arena, 1993 May 16
    - Page 209 A-Left: William Kennedy, Professor of English at the Albany premiere of the film based on his novel Ironweed., 1987
    - Page 209 B-Top Right: World Week., 1992
    - Page 209 C-Bottom Right: Novelist Toni Morrison receiving the Governor's Arts Award from Governor Mario Cuomo. Morrison joined the University at Albany faculty from 1985 to 1989 as the holder of the Schweitzer Chair in the Humanities., 1986
    - Page 210 A-Top: Ronald A. Bosco, Distinguished Service Professor of English., Undated
    - Page 210 B-Bottom: Shirley Jones, Distinguished Service Professor of Social Welfare., 1993
    - Page 211: Fuerza Latina, a student group, celebrates Hispanic heritage and culture with a celebration on the podium., Undated
    - Page 212: The 1993 Pan-Hellenic Council
    - Page 213 A-Top: "Campaign for Albany" kickoff: (l to r) Assemblyman Ed Sullivan, President Swygert, Campaign Chairman Gary R. Allen, '70, Assemblyman Anthony Casale, '69; J. Spenser Standish, President of the University at Albany Foundation., 1991 December 10
    - Page 213 B-Bottom: Homecoming 1990: (l to r) President Swygert, Howard Gross, President's Outstanding Young Alumni Service Award Winners Patty E. Salkin, '85 and Frederick Brewington, '79, Adrienne Brewington and Alumni Association President Susan VanHorn Shipherd, '64.
    - Page 214 A-Top Left: Mary Anne Croty, MPA '82, Governor Mario Cuomo's Director of State Operations, Undated
    - Page 214 B-Bottom Left: Susan Molinari, '80, '81, the first Albany graduate ever elected to Congress., ca. 1993
    - Page 214 C-Bottom Right: (l to r) President Swygert with Nina and Barry Wagman, national chairs of the Parent's Fund, who were presented with a University Chair at the President's Recognition Dinner., 1991
    - Page 215 A-Left: Derek Westbrook, '92, president of ASUBA, student assistant in the Educational Opportunities Program and 1992 Commencement student speaker., Undated
    - Page 215 B-Right: William Weitz, '92, Student Association President and Student Trustee to the SUNY Board of Trustees, 1993
    - Page 216: Torch night continues as one of the most enduring student traditions at Albany. It was renewed and enlarged in the 1980s., Undated
    - Page 217: Chancellor of the State University of New York D. Bruce Johnstone presents the Presidential Medallion to H. Patrick Swygert at the President's Inauguration., 1991 April 5
    - Page 224: About the Author: Kendall A. Birr, Professor Emeritus of History., Undated
    - Dustjacket Back Cover: The Belltower., Undated
- An Investigation into the Benefits of Having an Africana Studies Master's Degree, 1995 (Volume 31)